<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Campaigns on Game Manglement</title>
    <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Campaigns on Game Manglement</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shadowdark: Session Two, The Eye of the Lost</title>
      <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/shadowdark/session_two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/shadowdark/session_two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There were nine gods; that much is certain. But a void in the common knowledge burns brighter the more scholars study it. The fact is that two gods are lost to the ages. Their names purged from all ancestries’ memories. Their imagery vandalized, destroyed, or stolen. And yet, some texts from eons ago still mention these gods; though never by name. Not men, nor elves, nor dragons can make sense of this lack of information. Why were these gods purged from existence? Is this a punishment? Will they ever be known again? Scholars have wondered about those questions for centuries. Still, they hope that a new text, relic, or ancient location shall soon be unearthed and that it may hold the key to understanding the forgone past.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shadowdark: Session One, The Eye of the Lost</title>
      <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/shadowdark/session_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/shadowdark/session_one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There were nine gods; that much is certain. But a void in the common knowledge burns brighter the more scholars study it. The fact is that two gods are lost to the ages. Their names purged from all ancestries’ memories. Their imagery vandalized, destroyed, or stolen. And yet, some texts from eons ago still mention these gods; though never by name. Not men, nor elves, nor dragons can make sense of this lack of information. Why were these gods purged from existence? Is this a punishment? Will they ever be known again? Scholars have wondered about those questions for centuries. Still, they hope that a new text, relic, or ancient location shall soon be unearthed and that it may hold the key to understanding the forgone past.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultraviolet Grasslands: Session Two, Is that a gopher in your pants?</title>
      <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/uvg/session_two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/uvg/session_two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Having survived an attempted assassination from an unknown adversary (who seems to know a lot about Leo), our Heroes (capital H) head out into the Grasslands with the dwarves of Hog Enterprises, only to find that it is no safer than the city (and probably much worse).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-marut&#34;&gt;The Marut&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sun has barely started to colour the sky to the east of the Violet City on the second day of Redmonth, when our Heroes (capital H) gather at the industrial unit rented by the dwarves of Hog Enterprises. They met &lt;strong&gt;Nezod Smeltgut&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Alfobeth Hardbrew&lt;/strong&gt; a few days earlier when they were hired, but now meet the rest of the company:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultraviolet Grasslands: Session One, The Violet City</title>
      <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/uvg/session_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/uvg/session_one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This first session of Ultraviolet Grasslands using Cypher System started off well enough, after a few weeks of planning and a Session Zero that built the characters, but fell flat when the GM (me) was hit by a power cut and lost all network connectivity other than Discord on my cellphone. But hey, these things are sent to make us stronger. The second session went a little better, so here&amp;rsquo;s the write-up for both.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thousand Year Old Vampire: Journal of Grimaud de Fremay</title>
      <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/thousand_year_old/grimaud_journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/thousand_year_old/grimaud_journal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After hearing and reading so much about it, I decided to dive in and try out &lt;a href=&#34;https://thousandyearoldvampire.com/&#34;&gt;Thousand Year Old Vampire&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Hutchings. I have it in my head that I&amp;rsquo;d like to play a young Frankish knight from the Dark Age reign of Charlemagne, so I dig out my copy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/234701/PALADIN-Warriors-of-Charlemagne&#34;&gt;Paladin: Warriors of Charlemagne&lt;/a&gt; by Ruben in ’t Groen because not only is it a great historical RPG but it also provides a lot of the detail for the initial period that I&amp;rsquo;ll need.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downcrawl: Session Four</title>
      <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/downcrawl/session_four/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/downcrawl/session_four/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Swept away by the huge wave, Eirik and Sherman struggled to stay afloat for what seemed like hours, but was probably only a few minutes. Their feet first brushed, then settled on solid ground and, as the water drained away, they could just make out in the dim Fuzz light, that they had come to rest on a smooth stone floor. Beyond more than a dozen feet or so, what little light there was faded into a grey nothingness. Taking some time to gather themselves, they moved off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downcrawl: Session Three</title>
      <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/downcrawl/session_three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/downcrawl/session_three/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Standing in the doorway of the Alchemist&amp;rsquo;s Tower, the blood drained from Sherman&amp;rsquo;s face as he looked out onto streets swarming with green-eyed undead shambling and stumbling toward them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;How many?&amp;rdquo;, said Eirik, limbering up his massive shoulders and arms ready for the coming fight.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Err&amp;hellip; all of &amp;rsquo;em, I think&amp;rdquo;, said Sherman. Eirik&amp;rsquo;s face went blank with thought.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Door?&amp;rdquo;, asked Sherman. &amp;ldquo;Door&amp;rdquo;, Eirik nodded, and they started looking around for something to bar the door with.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downcrawl: Session Two</title>
      <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/downcrawl/session_two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/downcrawl/session_two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When last we saw our heroes, they had just been hired by local &amp;ldquo;businessman&amp;rdquo; and rather colorfully-dressed elf, Gwindore, to head for the catacombs far above Bone Falls and search for another party of adventurers sent in some weeks ago and who have not reappeared since. Gwindore was willing to pay them 10 keys each with another 5 keys per adventurer found alive. Cuthmar had still not appeared after the party lost him in the tunnels outside Bone Falls days ago, and now Celiophane had also gone missing, but intent on making a fast fortune, Sherman and Eirik set on their way.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downcrawl: Session One</title>
      <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/downcrawl/session_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/campaigns/downcrawl/session_one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When we first met our heroes, they were already well on the way to making a name for themselves. Sherman, Cuthmar, Eirik and Celiophane had taken on the task of rescuing a local merchant’s daughter from a band of marauding goblins, tracked the goblins to their cave-lair and fought their way to the goblin shaman who was about to make a blood sacrifice of the young girl. They figured they’d won, but with his dying breath the shaman uttered a dire curse. The cave shook, the ceiling started to crumble, and the floor gave way under the group. They fell, physically and mentally, into darkness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
