<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modiphius on Game Manglement</title>
    <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/tags/modiphius/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Modiphius on Game Manglement</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/tags/modiphius/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dune, Adventures in the Imperium RPG: Review</title>
      <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/posts/dune_rpg_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/posts/dune_rpg_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intended to coincide with the &lt;strong&gt;Dune 2021&lt;/strong&gt; movie, the much-anticipated Dune RPG from Modiphius has now been released while the movie has been delayed. How does it relate to the movie and what is it like? Here&amp;rsquo;s an initial review.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;game-system&#34;&gt;Game System&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like previous 2d20 system releases from &lt;strong&gt;Modiphius&lt;/strong&gt;, such as &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Adventures&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;John Carter&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Conan&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Dune&lt;/strong&gt; has the same basic game mechanic as those earlier systems: to attempt a task, the GM sets a difficulty level, the player rolls 2 or more d20 against the sum of two relevant attribute values, and the number of successes from that roll determines not only whether they succeed but how well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Star Trek Adventures: Search and Rescue</title>
      <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/articles/sta_sar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/articles/sta_sar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Adventures: Command Division&lt;/strong&gt; sourcebook introduced stats for new ships from Star Trek canon, many of which have either never been seen or seen only rarely on-screen. Among them is the &lt;strong&gt;Norway Class&lt;/strong&gt;, which was designed by the Advanced Starship Design Bureau for rapid emergency response. So, what&amp;rsquo;s it like being on the crew of one of these ships, what adventures can you have and how do you handle them?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Star Trek Adventures: Fighters</title>
      <link>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/articles/sta_fighters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pumbers.github.io/game-manglement/articles/sta_fighters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Command Division&lt;/strong&gt; sourcebook for &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Adventures&lt;/strong&gt; includes, almost hidden away in the &lt;strong&gt;Federation Small Craft&lt;/strong&gt; chapter, the details of the Federation Attack Fighter, also called the Zabathu&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; class (after an Andorian riding animal). This is really the first reference in the rules made to any sort of fighter class ship and, to be sure, such craft are rarely seen in Star Trek itself. Most ship battles on screen are between two or more &lt;strong&gt;capital ships&lt;/strong&gt; which make up the vast majority of any faction’s fleet. The biggest part played by fighters was during some of the major battles seen in Star Trek: Deep Space Nine, most notably the Second Battle of Deep Space Nine from “Call To Arms” (ep5x26) and The Invasion of Cardassia from the show’s finale episodes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
